<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; ibelieve</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 18:56:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Divine Exchange &#8211; Part 2</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/07/21/the-divine-exchange-part-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/07/21/the-divine-exchange-part-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 18:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am still on the theme of the divine exchange, still pondering the revelations of Derek Prince&#8217;s book &#8220;The Divine Exchange&#8221;. Last time we gazed in amazement as we were...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_7cc7a3a80de046ac889ea6da9a82e070~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_828,h_556,al_c,q_90/1bad17_7cc7a3a80de046ac889ea6da9a82e070~mv2.webp" alt="" width="841" height="565"/></figure>



<p id="viewer-2ipu4">I am still on the theme of the divine exchange, still pondering the revelations of Derek Prince&#8217;s book &#8220;The Divine Exchange&#8221;. Last time we gazed in amazement as we were reminded that Jesus bore our sinfulness and exchanged it for His righteousness and died our death that we would live His life. What an awesome Saviour we have.</p>



<p id="viewer-438pd">This week I am pondering the next aspect of the divine exchange. This is found in 2 Corinthians 8:9 &#8211;</p>



<h2 id="viewer-7irg2">For you know the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, that though He was rich, yet for your sakes He became poor, that you through His poverty might become rich.</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-7m7df"><p><em>Jesus became poor that we in return might become rich.</em></p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-6s2id">So when did Jesus become poor?</p>



<p id="viewer-4qt70">You may look at Jesus&#8217;s life and think He was poor; as He wanders the land with no place to lay His head. But, if you take a close look at His life you will see He never lacked anything. Everything He needed was always provided for Him. He never lacked anything; money, food, energy, wisdom, grace, love &#8211; nothing. Even when He sent the disciples out on their own they lacked nothing.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-d0c19">Luke 22:35</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-av732">And He said to them &#8220;When I sent you without money bag, knapsack, and sandals, did you lack anything?&#8221; So they said &#8220;Nothing&#8221;.</h2>



<p id="viewer-3jkhl">Jesus wasn&#8217;t poor in His life. He had everything He needed and everything He gave to others was from His riches. He had an abundance of everything for everyone who would ask of Him. He was rich in all things that out of the overflow of His riches He would minister, heal, love, help, deliver, and save all those that came and asked of Him. He never refused to help anyone. He never said He couldn&#8217;t help someone because He didn&#8217;t have what they needed. He met every need of every person who asked something of Him.</p>



<p id="viewer-cd73p">We read in the Word that Jesus and His disciples regularly gave to the poor.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-724tl">John 12:5</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-9grfs">Why was this fragrant oil not sold for three hundred denarii and given to the poor?</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-15mk0">John 13:29</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-dfrtt">For some thought, because Judas had the money box, that Jesus had said to him &#8220;Buy those things we need for the feast&#8221;, or that he should give something to the poor.</h2>



<p id="viewer-20vo9">If Jesus was poor, He would not have been able to give to the poor. You cannot give what you don&#8217;t have. We can only give from the overflow of what we have. He may not have walked around carrying lots of cash but time and time again when there was a need He provided for it. On some occasions His methods of providing for that need was unconventional to say the least.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-1pp8q">Matthew 17:27</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-6gnhm">Neverless, lest we offend them go to the sea, cast in a hook and take the fish that comes up first. And when you have opened its mouth, you will find a piece of money, take that and give it to them for Me and you.</h2>



<p id="viewer-bdg9t">Whatever He needed was provided for Him, even creation partnered with Him to provide what He needed. Jesus always lived in opposition of doing things the normal way. His whole ministry would turn the normal way of thinking about things completely upside down and inside out. He wants us to think out the box and expect the unexpected. He wants us to believe for the extra-ordinary.</p>



<p id="viewer-8kf3r">We see in Matthew 14:51-21 another unconventional account of how Jesus met the needs of over 5,000 people.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-6ef1l">That evening the disciples came to Him and said, “This is a remote place, and it’s already getting late. Send the crowds away so they can go to the villages and buy food for themselves.” But Jesus said, “That isn’t necessary—you feed them.” “But we have only five loaves of bread and two fish!” they answered. “Bring them here,” He said. Then He told the people to sit down on the grass. Jesus took the five loaves and two fish, looked up toward heaven, and blessed them. Then, breaking the loaves into pieces, He gave the bread to the disciples, who distributed it to the people. They all ate as much as they wanted, and afterward, the disciples picked up twelve baskets of leftovers. About 5,000 men were fed that day, in addition to all the women and children!</h3>



<p id="viewer-fdqpj">If Jesus was poor, would He really be able to feed all these people. He wouldn&#8217;t have the means to feed this crowd if He was poor. He needed to draw from an abundant supply to pull this off.</p>



<p id="viewer-82asi">The dictionary definition of poor is:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-6a1jm"><p>lacking sufficient money to live at a standard considered comfortable or normal in a society.</p></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-3vu3a"><p>deficient or lacking in.</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-dlic8">If He lacked in any aspect of His life He would not have been able to live as He did and impact the lives of all those around Him so radically.</p>



<p id="viewer-clr6k">When we read the Word we see that Jesus&#8217;s whole life depicts that of abundance. He always had all that He needed to do the will of God in His life. As well as having enough for Himself He was constantly meeting the needs of others. His supply was never exhausted. He constantly gave of His time, His provision, His wisdom, His healing, His money, His food. When there was a need He met the need. When He was asked to help, He helped. He gave freely from the abundance and overflow of His riches. So, I think we can safely say Jesus was not poor in His life.</p>



<p id="viewer-esvur">So when did He become poor for us?</p>



<p id="viewer-12at7">He became poor for us on the cross at Calvary! Jesus took all our poverty to the cross so that we no longer would have to live in lack.</p>



<p id="viewer-424cr">Deuteronomy 28:48 shows us clearly what absolute poverty looks like.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-766o5">Therefore, you shall serve your enemies, whom the Lord will send against you, in hunger, in thirst, in nakedness and in need of everything and He will put a yoke of iron on your neck until He has destroyed you.</h2>



<p id="viewer-d6mlm">These four words depict absolute poverty;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-4vio"><p>hunger, thirst, nakedness and in need of everything</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-arpbv">We see at the cross that Jesus endured all these things and became absolute poverty for us.</p>



<p id="viewer-83pkl">Jesus had been passed from pillar to post since the days of His arrest until the crucifixion. He would not have eaten for some time. He experienced HUNGER.</p>



<p id="viewer-e4q33">In John 19:28 we hear from the words of Jesus that as He hung on the cross He asked for something to drink. He experienced THIRST.</p>



<p id="viewer-4g244">In John 19:23 we read that the soldiers had Jesus&#8217;s garments that Had been stripped off of Him before He was nailed to the cross, and they cast lots to see who would get to keep them. Therefore, Jesus was completely naked on the cross, thus experiencing NAKEDNESS.</p>



<p id="viewer-dpl6i">As Jesus hung on the cross He had no possessions left. Everything had been stripped from Him. When He died He was buried in a borrowed tomb (Luke 23:50-53). He was IN NEED OF EVERYTHING.</p>



<p id="viewer-c5sbg">Each of these elements provide a complete picture of absolute poverty according to Deuteronomy 28:48. Thus we can say with great certainty that Jesus exactly and completely endured absolute poverty for you and for me.</p>



<p id="viewer-4f18b">Just like the other elements of the divine exchange Jesus endured our punishment that we might receive His reward. So when Jesus endured our poverty it was that we might receive His riches.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-1edds">2 Corinthians 9:8</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-7b4on">And God is able to make all grace abound toward you, that you, always having all sufficiency in all things, may have an abundance for every good work.</h2>



<p id="viewer-5d1sm">God, by His grace has made available everything we need to fullfil His perfect will and plan and purpose for our lives. Not because we have earned it, or done gone works for it, but because Jesus suffered and paid the penalty for us to receive it by faith as a gift from God.</p>



<p id="viewer-2sull">We, like Jesus, can live from a place of abundance, blessing those around us from the overflow of His riches in our lives. I don&#8217;t believe for one minute that His riches are limited to finances. I believe that His abundance and riches are in ALL things including your time, your talents, your skills, your wisdom, your spiritual maturity and the list goes on. We have each been given His riches as a gift, so that not only would all our needs be provided for but also the needs of those around us would be provided for too. But this only works completely and efficiently when each one of us, His kids, realise that we are to share with others the abudance that God has poured out on us. The Word says in Luke 3:11</p>



<h2 id="viewer-13g48">&#8220;He answered and said to them, &#8220;He who has two tunics, let him give to him who has none; and he who has food, let him do likewise.&#8221;</h2>



<p id="viewer-fq7ij">Our abundance may be someone else&#8217;s lack. By giving away the overflow of His riches we bless others and provide the needs of others. Acts 20:35 says:</p>



<h2 id="viewer-fr8n2">&#8230;It is more blessed to give than to receive.</h2>



<p id="viewer-2a0d2">His abundance of provision is not only that our needs would be met but that we would also bless those around us too. That we would share our blessings with others. In the early Church we see the believers solution for providing for the needs of all &#8211;</p>



<h2 id="viewer-8bqej">Acts 2:44-45</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-6jq7n">Now all who believed were together, and had all things in common, and sold their possessions and goods, and divided them among all, as anyone had need.</h2>



<p id="viewer-8r0ls">God has called us into His worldwide family. A family of brothes and sisters. His hearts desire is that we all would look out for each other, sharing our riches with those who have lack and vice versa. We will not all be rich in every area of our lives, we will need others to provide for us in areas where we lack. As we come together in greater unity and love every single believer&#8217;s need will be met.</p>



<p id="viewer-6cdrl">Over the last week I&#8217;ve been studying John 17:20-23, which is Jesus&#8217;s prayer for us, His children. Over and over Jesus prays that we would be one as Jesus and the Father are one. Unity of all believers seems to be the theme of His prayer.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-iao">I’m praying not only for them</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-7uoea">But also for those who will believe in Me</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-1nkmv">Because of them and their witness about Me.</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-drt0">The goal is for all of them to become one heart and mind—</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-2jo4j">Just as You, Father, are in Me and I in You,</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-60kla">So they might be one heart and mind with Us.</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-6mupq">Then the world might believe that You, in fact, sent Me.</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-dqmb7">The same glory You gave Me, I gave them,</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-ce7ic">So they’ll be as unified and together as We are—</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-vdnk">I in them and You in Me.</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-fuci3">Then they’ll be mature in this oneness,</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-b0abg">And give the godless world evidence</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-73msj">That You’ve sent Me and loved them</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-5g780">In the same way You’ve loved Me.</h3>



<p id="viewer-44tft">These are the words our Lord Jesus prayed for us just before He was betrayed and arrested. It is evident from His words that unity is His greatest desire for us His kids; to be one as He and the Father are One. Can you just take a pause here and think for a minute about what this means for us. Jesus wants us to be one; each believer to be one with each other. Moving and having our being as one. Just like Jesus and the Father. United in purpose, united in love, united in vision, united in belief, united in providing for each other, united in supporting one another.</p>



<p id="viewer-bco41">Jesus and the Father are One. They do nothing of themselves but everything they do together. They never work independently, but always work together in unity. Jesus told us that He never did anything of Himself, but only what He saw the Father do &#8211; John 5:19.</p>



<p id="viewer-64voa">So what does this mean for us, His kids? Unity is key if we are to truly live as God intended with everyone having their needs met and living from His abudance rather than our poverty.</p>



<p id="viewer-8cvqo">If we believe Jesus took our poverty and exchanged it for His abundance then we will live with an overflow from which to give to others, whether that is giving money, time, skills, wisdom, food, clothing or shelter.</p>



<p id="viewer-dmrht">Jesus prayed that we would be one and that in our oneness we would show the world that Jesus was real and was sent by God Almighty. If we are truly united then we will be built up in love for one another. As we love one another and meet the needs of others we bear witness to the world of the love of Jesus that flows through us. That as God loved Jesus so He loves us.</p>



<p id="viewer-1p4ac">The love that we have for others will testify to the love of God that is in each of us. How we treat people; how we care for them and love them will witness to the world of something greater at work in our lives. By our love and care of each other people in the world will notice that we are different, that we love with action and purpose.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-7kvj">John 13:35</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-fs3oq">By this all will know that you are My disciples, if you have love for one another.</h2>



<p id="viewer-6h0qf">It is our love for one another that will show the world who we belong to. If we truly understand what Jesus has done for us on the cross then we will live believing that we have access to His abundance and our needs will be met. If we truly live united, brother and sister together, then none of us should lack anything. Each sister and brother will provide from their own abundance to help others in their lack. This may be to lend a helping hand, do a random act of kindness, pray, love, teach, or encourage, as well as giving of our time, talents, money, food, shelter, clothes. The list can go on and on. No matter how rich or poor we are in this world, we are all rich in the kingdom of God and all have something to give to others from the abundance of Jesus&#8217;s riches, freely given to each one of us.</p>



<p id="viewer-7tdge">So just as Jesus endured our poverty to give us His riches, then live from the abundance of His riches today and not from your own poverty.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-7mequ"><p>According to what was done for you on the cross, you lack nothing today.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/07/21/the-divine-exchange-part-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Divine Exchange</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/07/21/the-divine-exchange/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/07/21/the-divine-exchange/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Divine Exchange Over the last few weeks I have been studying the Divine Exchange with my online Church Group. Some time back we spoke about the desire we had...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h1>The Divine Exchange</h1>



<p id="viewer-foo">Over the last few weeks I have been studying the Divine Exchange with my online Church Group. Some time back we spoke about the desire we had to find out exactly what Jesus has done for us on the cross and how we can live in His resurrection power.</p>



<p id="viewer-d4a1c">We came across a book by Derek Prince called The Divine Exchange. This book opened our eyes to great and wonderful truths. Truths that we already knew but didn&#8217;t really understand. The revelation we received from this study has birthed a deeper love and adoration for our Saviour Jesus and reignited a passionate relationship with our Father.</p>



<p id="viewer-5pr1v">I pray you will be greatly blessed by this study too.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_7cc7a3a80de046ac889ea6da9a82e070~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_828,h_556,al_c,q_90/1bad17_7cc7a3a80de046ac889ea6da9a82e070~mv2.webp" alt=""/></figure>



<h2 id="viewer-2q76">&#8220;Come to Me, all you who are weary and burdened, and I will give you rest.&#8221;</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-2008a">Matthew 11:28</h2>



<p id="viewer-34eqt">This is an open invitation from Jesus. He extends His invitation to each one of us today to come and find rest from our emotional struggles, our financial worries, our health concerns, our weariness of life, and all things that torment us. He calls out to us today to come to Him.</p>



<p id="viewer-f7nat">But, how do we come to Him?</p>



<p id="viewer-fcosl">God has made a way for us to come to Jesus and enter into His rest. He has the perfect answer to all our burdens, all that torments us and makes us weary. His answer is the cross of Christ. The cross is the answer to all our questions and the one thing that can silence all the accusations of the enemy and rend him powerless. The cross is our greatest weapon when we know its true power.</p>



<p id="viewer-3itbc">We have an enemy. An enemy that knows what happened on the cross. An enemy that knows the power of the cross. His plan is to keep us in deception and unbelief. To keep us from a true understanding of what happened on the cross. To keep us from the whole truth. If he can keep us looking to ourselves instead of the cross, then he has the victory.</p>



<p id="viewer-6v9oc">If we are to live the victorious life that Christ died for us to have, we need to know the truth of the cross and exactly what took place there.</p>



<p id="viewer-pot">Jesus&#8217;s whole life led to the cross. His sacrificial death was His life purpose. He was born to die.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-eo19l">For by one offering He has perfected forever those who are being sanctified.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-3ls0e">Hebrews 10:14</h2>



<p id="viewer-7d37h">This is a powerful verse. I think you need to read it again, slowly!</p>



<h2 id="viewer-f3mi9">For by one offering He has perfected forever those who are being sanctified.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-4725b">Hebrews 10:14</h2>



<p id="viewer-43j09">So, through Jesus&#8217;s death, He offered Himself as a living sacrifice for all of us. He made us perfect by His works; not by anything we have done, but because of everything He did. He gave His perfect, sinless life in exchange for our sinful, disobedient lives.</p>



<p id="viewer-b7jji">God, in His wisdom, had a master plan that would see an end to humanity falling into a lost eternity and would reconcile all men to Himself. His plan wasn&#8217;t reliant on man. And the plan didn&#8217;t need man to participate for it to come to pass.</p>



<p id="viewer-akkno">We all have been brought up in different backgrounds. We all have different colours of skin, different colours of hair. Some of us have been brought up in wealth and some in poverty. Regardless of where we have come from and what the world thinks of us, we must all come to the same place if we are to truly receive the answer to all our questions and walk in the resurrection power.</p>



<p id="viewer-1jj8v">The place where each of us must come is to the cross. We need to have a revelation of what Jesus has done for us. We need to repent of our rebellion against Him and receive all that He died to give us. We must fully understand all that He has done for us if we are to walk in His resurrection power.</p>



<p id="viewer-4sd9n">We see in Isaiah 53:10-11 a description of the righteous servant that was prophesied to come and take the penalty for sin on Himself and make atonement for all humanity.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-blqba">Yet it was the Lord’s will to crush Him and cause Him to suffer, and though the Lord makes His life an offering for sin, He will see His offspring and prolong His days, and the will of the Lord will prosper in His hand. After He has suffered, He will see the light of life and be satisfied; by His knowledge my righteous servant will justify many, and He will bear their iniquities.</h2>



<p id="viewer-a0hel">From the beginning of time it was God&#8217;s plan for Jesus to come and take upon Himself all the sins of the world. Through all that Jesus would do on the cross, we would reap the rewards. Sin had to be atoned for.</p>



<p id="viewer-f6ter">From the very beginning man choose to go his own way, denying the wisdom of the almighty and following his own selfish desires. This we see in Isaiah 53:6 &#8211;</p>



<h2 id="viewer-1m6q2">We all, like sheep, have gone astray, each of us has turned to our own way; and the Lord has laid on Him the iniquity of us all.</h2>



<p id="viewer-p5qd">This is where we see the inherant problem of all humanity. We have all turned, each one of us, to our own way; forsaking fellowship with our divine maker. We may not have committed adultery or murdered, or stolen, but each one of us at some point in our lives have gone our own way and disregarded God&#8217;s instruction and guidance. We have all rebelled against God and lived in disobedience to Him.</p>



<p id="viewer-9csvm">So, the purpose of the cross was to pay the penalty, divinely exchanging the evil that was due all mankind for their iniquities and sinful ways for all the good that was due the perfect Son of God for His sinless life. Jesus endured all the evil consequences that were due us by divine justice for all our iniquities and rebelliousness and in exchange God offers us all the good that was due to the sinless, obedient Jesus.</p>



<p id="viewer-6t3ce">This divine exchange was set in place by our Father in heaven, by His lavish grace. There is not one of us who deserved such an offer of outrageous proportions, where Jesus would take our filthy rags and exchange them for His lavish priestly robes.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-1meu1">God made Him who had no sin to be sin for us, so that in Him we might become the righteousness of God.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-2dmpl">2 Corinthians 5:21</h2>



<p id="viewer-2rr6e">Paul shows us that through Jesus and the work of the cross, atonement was made for us, not by our own efforts, but by God&#8217;s own righteousness. It must be accepted by faith. It cannot be earned.</p>



<p id="viewer-4tcp1">Jesus became our sin. He took on Himself all of humanities iniquities from the foundation of the earth to the end of days.</p>



<p id="viewer-bpn5i">He absorbed all our rebellious ways. All the consequences and punishment due humanity for their sin was put upon Him. The sinless Saviour bore our sin. In exchange for this He offers us His righteousness. His right standing with the Father. A mended relationship; a restored identity.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-b0j28"><p>What a Saviour!</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-c2e5d">Do we really understand what that means? That Jesus gave us His righteousness. Think about that for a minute&#8230;</p>



<p id="viewer-73lg0">Jesus was perfect in the eyes of the Father. He was with the Father from the foundation of the earth. He knew the Father, heard the Father, saw the Father. We read in Matthew 3:17-</p>



<h2 id="viewer-87i8">And suddenly a voice <em>came</em> from heaven, saying, “This is My beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.”</h2>



<p id="viewer-16v7">Jesus holds a place of honour with the Father. Jesus is sinless, obedient, and in a right relationship with the Father. Jesus exchanges His right standing and right living for our sinful, disobedient and rebellious lives. It is mind blowing to think that our God would go so far for us, to reconcile us back to Himself. He did it all for us.</p>



<p id="viewer-boge5">God knew our weaknesses and that we needed a rescue plan of gigantic proportions. He knew we would not be able to bridge the gap back to Him by ourselves. From the very beginning we get glimpses of the perfect plan of redemption to come.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-d4eal">And I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your seed and her Seed. He shall bruise your head, and you shall bruise His heel.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-6fqhk">Genesis 3:15</h2>



<p id="viewer-3nf2g">At the perfect time in history He steps down from HIs heavenly throne, into humanity, and takes our punishment on Himself.</p>



<p id="viewer-crje4">He instigated the rescue plan; putting it into place at just the right time. He took the place a guilty humanity; paying all the costs in His own body with His own life.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-79a43"><p>What a beautiful Saviour!</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-7mjnc">So why did He have to die? Why couldn&#8217;t He just make things right without dying? We see from scripture that the price of sin is death.</p>



<p id="viewer-7dhuc">Ezekiel 18:4 says</p>



<p id="viewer-1pbs0">&#8230;The soul who sins shall die.</p>



<p id="viewer-copk3">James 1:15</p>



<p id="viewer-9gur4">&#8230;sin, when it is full-grown brings forth death.</p>



<p id="viewer-5mam9">Jesus knew that to atone for our sins He would have to die. Throughout the old testament we see foreshadows of the cross. We read about the sacrificial lamb being sacrificed for the sins of the people once a year. We read how the sins of the people were transferred to the animals and then they were killed. The blood of these animals covered the sins of men for one year. All these old testament accounts point to the cross and the ultimate sacrifice of our Lord Jesus.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-dj43e">But we do see Jesus, who was made lower than the angels for a little while, now crowned with glory and honor because He suffered death, so that by the grace of God He might taste death for everyone.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-5djii">Hebrews 2:9</h2>



<p id="viewer-ev7ru">He not only paid the price for my sin, but the sins of all humanity. He died the death of every single soul that ever would be, even those He knew would reject Him. He died our death that we might gain His life.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-1l2sj">For the wages of sin is death, but the gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-18h2k">Romans 6:23</h2>



<p id="viewer-5au0c">Our punishment was death. But, Jesus gives us a gift of eternal life. If we would just believe in Him, believe what He has done for us and receive from Him all that He died for us to have. God&#8217;s plan for humanity never included death. It was by one man&#8217;s sin that death entered into the equation.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-29s3b">When Adam sinned, sin entered the world. Adam’s sin brought death, so death spread to everyone, for everyone sinned. Yes, people sinned even before the law was given. But it was not counted as sin because there was not yet any law to break. Still, everyone died—from the time of Adam to the time of Moses—even those who did not disobey an explicit commandment of God, as Adam did. Now Adam is a symbol, a representation of Christ, who was yet to come. But there is a great difference between Adam’s sin and God’s gracious gift. For the sin of this one man, Adam, brought death to many. But even greater is God’s wonderful grace and His gift of forgiveness to many through this other man, Jesus Christ. And the result of God’s gracious gift is very different from the result of that one man’s sin. For Adam’s sin led to condemnation, but God’s free gift leads to our being made right with God, even though we are guilty of many sins.</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-cob7h">Romans 5:12-16</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-8lpbg"><p>Hallelujah, what a Saviour.</p></blockquote>



<h2 id="viewer-62c8v"></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-79ivi">Jesus became sin for us, that we would receive His righteousness.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-cqeh5">Jesus died our death that we would live an eternal life.</h2>



<p id="viewer-c3mol">The law demanded death for sin. God the Father, God the Son and God the Holy Spirit, in their love of humanity and their desire to bring a fallen world back into a right relationship with them, took the punishment and paid the ultimate price.</p>



<p id="viewer-ccev1">Do you know there is nothing more to be done for our salvation?</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-8d5v2"><p>&#8220;You contribute nothing to your salvation except the sin that made it necessary.&#8221; Jonathan Edwards</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-7jlhu">Is it only me or do you too find this mind blowing?</p>



<p id="viewer-7v8lh">Psalm 73:25 says &#8211;</p>



<h2 id="viewer-7sqs">Whom have I in heaven but You?</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-emjot">And there is none upon earth that I desire besides You. My flesh and my heart fail; But God is the strength of my heart and my portion forever.</h2>



<p id="viewer-d2tv6">Thank the Lord for all He has done for you. Receive and accept His sacrifice, His blood, His love for you. Believe He died just for you. Believe He loves you so much He died for you.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-3ia03">For God so loved the world that He gave His one and only Son, that whosoever believes in Him shall not perish, but have everlasting life.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-7bkof">John 3:16</h2>



<p id="viewer-aps21">Hear Him call out your name today and choose this day to believe on Him. To believe His word, to believe He died just for you, to believe He loves you. To draw closer to Him and rest in the assurance that the work of salvation has been done for you, once for all. He loves you so much He died for you.</p>



<p id="viewer-3q4s5">Remember the cross is the answer to everything the enemy will throw at you. The cross is the greatest expression of love the world has ever seen. The cross is our freedom.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_2593b50af82741269e3347ac33711f67~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_750,h_469,al_c,q_20/file.jpg" alt="" width="847" height="529"/></figure>



<p id="viewer-e5gq2">If you would like a free download of the Divine Exchange by Derek Prince then copy and paste the link below:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://www.derekprince.org/Articles/1000132017/DPM_USA/Contact/Divine_Exchange_form/The_Divine_Exchange.aspx
</div></figure>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/07/21/the-divine-exchange/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spiritual Check up</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/07/21/spiritual-check-up/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/07/21/spiritual-check-up/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disappointment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual check up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=377</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you are in a place where you feel your spiritual life has halted abruptly or is stagnant and you can&#8217;t seem to move beyond where you are then maybe...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_15d11739d08f4752afce1a1cc04bcd0d~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_797,h_477,al_c,q_90/1bad17_15d11739d08f4752afce1a1cc04bcd0d~mv2.webp" alt="" width="849" height="508"/></figure>



<p id="viewer-aesp1">If you are in a place where you feel your spiritual life has halted abruptly or is stagnant and you can&#8217;t seem to move beyond where you are then maybe you need to check your heart and ask Holy Spirit to reveal aspects in your life that may be binding you to the past, to sinful ways, to unbelief, or to unforgiveness. It is essential for a healthy walk with the Lord to constantly check our hearts and minds, allowing Holy Spirit to reveal the things that are leading us in a wrong path whether through wrong thinking or wrong teachings; to free us from deception and bring us ever closer to Jesus and His truth.</p>



<p id="viewer-je1j">I have detailed below different emotions that influence our lives and either hinder us or aid us in our walk with the Lord. As you read this post open your heart to the leading of Holy Spirit and honestly assess your spiritual condition, taking note of anything Holy Spirit reveals to you so you may address them in your life.</p>



<p id="viewer-77ae9">Don&#8217;t hold on to things that hinder you from the presence of the Lord. Lay everything down in submission to Him knowing that His plans and purposes are perfect and His ways are above and beyond what we could imagine or desire for ourselves.</p>



<p id="viewer-4qagl">One thing I have learned with the Lord is that He never pushes us into make changes in our lives. He reveals His truths then allows you to make your own choices. Often we remain stagnant in our walk when we refuse to take heed of what He is showing us and follow His leading obediently. We will remain where we are until we deal with the issues at hand. God will not move us on in our walk until we rectify these issues in our lives.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_2593b50af82741269e3347ac33711f67~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_925,h_578,al_c,q_90/1bad17_2593b50af82741269e3347ac33711f67~mv2.webp" alt=""/></figure>



<p id="viewer-4pdv7">The first emotion is forgiveness.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-6pcjn"><strong>Forgiveness</strong></h3>



<p id="viewer-7gdbc">Forgiveness is an essential part of being a Christian. If you seek intimacy and maturity with God and long for peace and serenity in your life, then it is essential that in all things you learn to forgive. If you want to go deeper with God any unforgiveness you hold in your heart will hamper deeper intimacy with Him.</p>



<p id="viewer-ench1">The Bible tells us in Matthew 6:14 &#8211;</p>



<h2 id="viewer-5o027">&#8220;For if you forgive men their trespasses, your heavenly Father will also forgive you. But if you do not forgive men their trespasses, neither will your Father forgive your trespasses.&#8221;</h2>



<p id="viewer-715rg">God is clear on unforgiveness and the peril for each believer to remain in unforgiveness; irrespective of who has wronged you and what has been done to you. The Word tells us that we must forgive.</p>



<p id="viewer-8461u">In Matthew 18:23-35 we see the account of the unforgiving servant. The king wanted the servant and his family sold to repay the money they owed the king. The servant bowed before the king and begged for mercy. The king had compassion on him, released him and forgave him the debt. But then the servant seeks out his fellow servant who owes him money; (a much less debt than what he owed the king). He demands payment from this fellow servant; ruthlessly attacking him. This man cries out for mercy, begging him to give him time to pay his debt. Unlike the king, this servant has no compassion and mercy and throws this fellow servant into prison until he can pay his debt. When the king hears what has been done he immediately calls the servant to himself. He questions the servant saying &#8211;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-106ii"><p>&#8220;I forgave you all that debt because you begged me. Should you not also have had compassion on your fellow servant, just as I had pity on you?&#8221;</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-8marh">The king was very angry and delivered him to the torturers until he should pay all that was due to him.</p>



<p id="viewer-aiea3">Verse 35 tells us</p>



<h2 id="viewer-fo1s0">&#8220;So My heavenly Father also will do to you if each of you, from his heart, does not forgive his brother his trespasses.&#8221;</h2>



<p id="viewer-101pj">This account of the king and the unforgiving servant is a picture of Jesus the King and every believer. We have been forgiven much. Each one of us sinful from birth owing a huge debt to the King of kings.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-em34n">Romans 3:23</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-5omvh">For all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God.</h2>



<p id="viewer-dqg13">Each believer has received the grace and mercy of Christ by the washing of our sin by His precious blood.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-2qobv">1 Peter 1:18-19</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-7phm5">knowing that you were not redeemed with corruptible things, like silver or gold, from your aimless conduct received by tradition from your fathers, but with the precious blood of Christ, as of a lamb without blemish and without spot.</h3>



<p id="viewer-6vpi9">We didn&#8217;t deserve the master of the universe coming to earth as a human and paying the debt owed by us. We didn&#8217;t do anything to earn His forgiveness and He paid our debt before we even came to be.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-29slj">Romans 5:8</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-cafi4">But God demonstrates His own love toward us, in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us.</h2>



<p id="viewer-8q9h1">Our perfect saviour wants us to forgive because He doesn&#8217;t want us to carry burdens that are not ours to carry. He doesn&#8217;t want us to become the judge and the jury against our fellow human beings. He warns us the cost of judging others</p>



<h2 id="viewer-1dj37">Matthew 7:1-2</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-9tkbl">Judge not, that you be not judged. For with what judgement you judge, you will be judged; and with the measure you use, it will be measured back to you.</h2>



<p id="viewer-evktc">All God asks is that we bring any offense, any hurt, any frustration, any argument, anything that takes our peace, to the altar and lay it down as a sacrifice to God. For Him to deal with and heal our hurts and release us from the bondage of unforgiveness. This releases our grip from the throat of the wrong doer and allows God to work in both us and them.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-cooep">Matthew 7:12</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-i55p">Therefore, whatever you want men to do to you, do also to them, for this is the Law and the Prophets.</h2>



<p id="viewer-8jd70">God will always deal with us personally. It is not our job to put other people right, but it is always our job to keep ourselves right. The consequences of drifting from the truth could be catastrophic.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-fbasu">Jeremiah 17:10</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-f6se">I, the Lord, search the heart, I test the mind, even to give every man according to his ways, according to the fruit of his doings.</h2>



<p id="viewer-fpp8r">So you see, God searches our hearts and gives us according to our ways and according to the fruits in our lives. If we harbour unforgiveness our fruit will be bitter and rotten. Our minds will be plagued with stomach churning thoughts of our wrong doer. We will justify in our minds a rightful revenge on those who hurt us and remove ourselves from the cover and protection of the Lord.</p>



<p id="viewer-a99ms">The Bible tells us</p>



<h2 id="viewer-8fe16">Deuteronomy 32:35</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-deat9">Vengeance is Mine, and recompense; their foot shall slip in due times; for the day of their calamity is at hand, and the things to come hasten upon them.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-ch6cr">Romans 12:19</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-bdr9p">Beloved, do not avenge yourselves, but rather give place to wrath; for it is written &#8220;Vengeance is Mind, I will repay&#8221;, says the Lord.</h2>



<p id="viewer-9hqad">Take all your offenses to the cross, lay them down, forgive the person and release them from the grip of your hand. You may have to say a thousand times a day &#8220;I forgive them&#8221;, but bit by bit you will say it less, the stomach churning will grow less and less and the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and minds through Christ Jesus &#8211; Philippians 4:7.</p>



<p id="viewer-5k4f3">Jesus bore all your sins at the cross and forgave you, the least you can do is forgive others.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-48fst">Luke 23:34</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-1ukuu">Then Jesus said, &#8220;Father, forgive them, for they do not know what they do.&#8221;</h2>



<p id="viewer-f04rc">Take a leap of faith and put this into practice in your life. I know for a fact it will radically change you life, your attitudes and your spiritual walk with the Lord.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_bc55710992734037becf31f7967820f3~mv2.png/v1/fill/w_558,h_554,al_c,lg_1,q_95/1bad17_bc55710992734037becf31f7967820f3~mv2.webp" alt=""/></figure>



<p id="viewer-748c8">The second emotion I would like to bring before you is disappointment.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-8ff9f"><strong>Disappointment</strong></h3>



<p id="viewer-13fee">Disappointment can also harbour grudges and cause us to live a life of unambition and protection.</p>



<p id="viewer-4ops3">When you have had hopes and dreams in your life and for whatever reason these hopes and dreams have not came to pass, then this can leave you with disappointments. Disappointments, like unforgiveness, can rot away at your heart, steal your joy and reduce your hope. These disappointments stop us from achieving our God given purposes. They keep us from flying high and reaching for the skies. They keep us grounded and unsure of what may happen to us in our lives.</p>



<p id="viewer-emkf2">My advice is that if you know of any time in your life where you have been disappointed. Whether that is because of yourself, other people or even God, I urge you to address these disappointments before God. Talk to Him in prayer, telling Him everything that has disappointed you; confessing to God how that has affected you and hurt you. Lay down your emotions, your failed dreams, your dashed hopes; take them all to the altar asking the Lord to release you from the weight of carrying them. As you hand over these disappointments to the Lord ask Holy Spirit to release healing into your spirit. Then remind yourself that God has a better plan for your life.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-3ug5n">Ephesians 3:20</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-f3p2d">Now to Him who is able to do exceedingly abundantly above all that we ask or think, according to the power that works in us.</h2>



<p id="viewer-ds2s1">Don&#8217;t allow the enemy to keep you focused on past failures and lost experiences. Look to the Lord for what He will do for you. For God uses all things for good for those who love Him.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-9p1ct">Romans 8:28</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-1cog">And we know that all things work together for good to those who love God, to those who are the called according to His purpose.</h2>



<p id="viewer-3hhju">We do not need to carry all these extra burdens, Jesus has told us that His yoke is easy and His burden is light. If you are struggling under a heavy burden then it is not of the Lord. Seek guidance from the Holy Spirit and come clean with what is burdening you and allow the Holy Spirit to heal and restore your peace.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_e49c9b0819114880891060173a84140b~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_924,h_528,al_c,lg_1,q_90/1bad17_e49c9b0819114880891060173a84140b~mv2.webp" alt=""/></figure>



<p id="viewer-aacnl">The last emotion I want to look at is surrender.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-847r6"><strong>Surrender</strong></h3>



<p id="viewer-43c14">Surrender to God&#8217;s will in everything. So what does surrender mean &#8211;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-95rve"><p>stop resisting to an enemy or opponent and submit to their authority</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-bj09b">Surrender is giving control to another person and allowing that person to have their way in your life. Trouble comes when we grip on for dear life to control of our lives and don&#8217;t relinquish control to the master. It can be a scary thing to hand over control of our lives. Here in the western world we are taught very much to be independent and do things for ourselves. Handing over control to someone else is not in our nature. However, if we are to fulfil our calling and walk a life worthy of what Jesus has died for us to have, we must surrender everything to Him and be guided by the One who knows all things. We must die to ourselves and allow Him to live through us. It&#8217;s not about us it&#8217;s all about Him.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-anvru">Galatians 2:20</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-379aa">I have been crucified with Christ, it is no longer I who live, but Christ lives in me, and the life I now live in the flesh I live by faith in the son of God who loved me and gave Himself for me.</h2>



<p id="viewer-9j2nf">We are not surendering to an abuser, to someone who seeks to harm us. We are surrendering our lives into the hands of the perfect saviour who came to give us life and life in abundance (John 10:10). We are surrendering into the hands that were pierced for our sins. Our God is faithful and can be trusted.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-8ge1b">Lamentations 3:23-24</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-arjqr">Through the Lord&#8217;s mercies we are not consumed, because His compassions fail not. They are new every morning; Great is Your faithfulness.</h2>



<p id="viewer-8njma">We have a God that knows what we need before we ask for it.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-2slfa">Matthew 6:8</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-al102">Therefore do not be like them. For your Father knows the things you have need of before you ask Him.</h2>



<p id="viewer-2puo5">His plans are to give you peace and not evil, to give you a future and a hope &#8211; Jeremiah 29:11. He is a good, good Father and He knows how to give good gifts to His children &#8211;</p>



<h2 id="viewer-dtghs">Matthew 7:11</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-1934l">If you then, being evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father who is in heaven give good things to those who ask Him.</h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-33cuj"><p>What are you waiting for?</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-eoem1">To surrender to Him is to live with no regret; to live with no worry; to live with expectancy and adventure. To live in surrender means to trust Him.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-bsbbk">Proverbs 3:5-6</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-8av5b">Trust in the Lord will all your heart and lean not on your own understanding. In all your ways acknowledge Him and He will direct your paths.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-918m2">Let go and let God take control.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-6e6t3"></h2>



<p id="viewer-ae5g2">I pray these words will bring you to a place of repentence and submission to God, the author and perfector of our faith, the one who is able to keep you from falling.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-f3mpd">Hebrews 12:2</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-1t6gu">Looking unto Jesus, the author and finisher of our faith, who for the joy that was set before Him endured the cross, despising the shame, and has sat down at the right hand of the throne of God.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-8v3jl">Jude 1:24</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-fg37e">Now to Him who is able to keep you from stumbling, and to present you faultless before the presence of His glory with exceeding joy, To God our Saviour, who alone is wise, Be glory and majesty, dominion and power, both now and forever. Amen</h2>



<p id="viewer-17i67">Trust in Him who is able to keep you from stumbling. Don&#8217;t wait another minute. Go seek the Lord and surrender everything that ensnares you and keeps you from His glorious presence.</p>



<p id="viewer-4h9f2">I pray you will be blessed with this short study and that it has given you some insight into what can cause you problems in your walk with the Lord. I pray you can see the benefit of laying down your disappointments, forgiving those who have hurt you and surrendering all things into His hands. I pray the Lord grants you the grace to lay all things down and leave them on the altar of sacrifice. I promise you, if you do these things you will know peace like never before and you will experience His easy yoke and His light burden. Bless you.</p>



<p id="viewer-4diak">Please leave a comment if you have any questions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/07/21/spiritual-check-up/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Defeating Giants!</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/07/21/defeating-giants/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/07/21/defeating-giants/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=375</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We all face giants in our lives. Some cause great destruction and seek to consume our whole lives while others are more subtle and can often operate beneath our level...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_0573456daa784135b2b385a378f3c519~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_420,h_235,al_c,lg_1,q_90/1bad17_0573456daa784135b2b385a378f3c519~mv2.webp" alt="" width="840" height="470"/></figure>



<p id="viewer-fj1u7">We all face giants in our lives. Some cause great destruction and seek to consume our whole lives while others are more subtle and can often operate beneath our level of consciousness and go un-recognised for some time.</p>



<p id="viewer-4u75u">Over the last 30 years, journeying with the Lord, He has taught me not to fight giants in my own strength, no matter what type they might be. The Lord has taught me that the only way to fight giants is with the word of God.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-e2er4"><em>For the word of God is living and powerful, and sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing even to the division of soul and spirit, and of joints and marrow, and is a discerner of the thoughts and intents of the heart.</em></h3>



<h3 id="viewer-e9rq5"><em>Hebrews 4:12</em></h3>



<p id="viewer-apsu0">The word of God is living and powerful, changing and transforming everyone who hears it. It is our sword, our weapon.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-653f3"></h3>



<h2 id="viewer-3e51d"><em>Ephesians 6:17</em></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-9tahu"><em>And take the helmet of salvation, and the sword of the Spirit, which is the word of God.</em></h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-2olvd"><p>If God has given us such a powerful weapon, then why do we not use it to fight the giants?</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-dba5m">About 6 years ago I found myself in the most terrifying place I have ever been. I had attended my Church prayer meeting that evening and as I knelt in prayer beside my bed later that night I asked the Lord this question &#8211;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-402ks"><p>&#8220;Am I afraid to die?&#8221;</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-7b43v">Instantly, I was hit with a great wave of fear, almost like a tsunami that consumed me in wave after wave of emotion. I was in the grips of something terrifying and I didn&#8217;t know what to do. I was so scared I couldn&#8217;t even cry out to God. All I could do was bury my head in my pillow and close my eyes to what was going on. By God&#8217;s grace I was able to sleep.</p>



<p id="viewer-9em8">When I awoke the next day fear hit me all over again like a tsunami that never seemed to stop coming.</p>



<p id="viewer-b2a7h">For the next couple of weeks I couldn&#8217;t eat, I couldn&#8217;t read my Bible, I couldn&#8217;t pray, I couldn&#8217;t watch TV or hold a conversation. I couldn&#8217;t do anything without being twisted with fear from the inside out. When I went to work all I could say was &#8220;Help me Jesus&#8221; over and over. My whole body shook with fear all day long, so much so that I was constantly dizzy and unsteady on my feet. Amazingly the Lord gave me strength to get through each day and at night He brought peace to me so that I was able to sleep and escape the fear.</p>



<p id="viewer-63ibb">Everything at this point scared me. Even the mention of God terrified me. There was no escape in my waking hours from the torment of fear. Then, one day&#8230;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-f3b3t"><p><em>I turned to scriptures for comfort and help.</em></p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-knf9">I opened my Bible at 1 John 4:18-</p>



<h2 id="viewer-17kj6"><em>There is no fear in love;</em></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-6fu38"><em>but perfect love casts out fear,</em></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-ist"><em>because fear involves torment.</em></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-6gdiq"><em>But he who fears has not been made perfect in love.</em></h2>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-9pbki"><p>This verse jumped out at me.</p></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-9nt7o"><p>Perfect love casts out ALL fear.</p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-1p9v4">So, I thought to myself &#8220;What is perfect love?&#8221; Surely, I thought, the love of Jesus is perfect love. He has perfected His love for me through His finished work on the cross. And His Holy Spirit lives inside of me, meaning that the perfect love of Jesus abides in His Holy Spirit who abides in me. If the Holy Spirit abides in me then perfect love abides in me and where perfect love is there is no fear. All I had to do was believe it and declare it.</p>



<p id="viewer-6ob9k">So, for days I would repeat again and again &#8211;</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-879t1"><p><em>&#8220;Perfect love casts out all fear. My Saviour Jesus is perfect love and He lives inside of me through His Spirit, filling me with His perfect love. Where His perfect love is all fear is cast out.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-b05fr">I spoke this over myself again and again. Sometimes repeating it dozens of times in a day. The fear didn&#8217;t go away instantly but it did subside as the days went on. I just kept declaring this passage of scripture over myself repeatedly. Over time I realised I was saying this verse less and less and the chaos inside of me was growing calmer and calmer. The peace that surpasses all understanding grew stronger and stronger upon my life. My appetite returned, the anxiety and fear left, the shaking and dizzy spells stopped and before long my peace had returned completely.</p>



<p id="viewer-98bmg">When we fight using God&#8217;s weapons the giants that once paralysed us become like ants in our hands. All it takes is simple faith. All we need to do is take a verse, believe what is says and declare it over our lives. As we declare the truth of God&#8217;s word, the word, which is living and powerful, delivers us from the lie that binds us.</p>



<p id="viewer-1ngj0">In the song &#8220;The Voice of Truth&#8221; by Casting Crowns the chorus says</p>



<p id="viewer-88bop">&#8220;But the voice of truth tells me a different story The voice of truth says, &#8220;Do not be afraid!&#8221; The voice of truth says, &#8220;This is for My glory&#8221; Out of all the voices calling out to me I will choose to listen and believe the voice of truth.&#8221;</p>



<p id="viewer-2u7np">You see no matter what giant is coming at you today you have a choice whether to believe the voice of the enemy or the voice of truth. Whether it is coming after your health, your marriage, your family, your finances, or your faith, the truth of the word tells us we have a Saviour that has won against every giant and He has overcome everything that would come against us.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-bdu9s"><em>John 16:33</em></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-eugfg"><em>These things I have spoken to you, that in Me you may have peace. In the world you will have tribulation, but be of good cheer, <u>I have overcome the world.</u></em></h2>



<p id="viewer-882hn">Be of good cheer, Jesus has overcome the world and everything in it. His promises are for us to declare over our lives. He has given us His word, His manual for every situation that would come our way. It frees us from the things that ensnare us and seek to destroy our connection with God.</p>



<p id="viewer-2nst5">We serve a perfect Father and His loving kindness is like no other.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-1kb5r"><p><em>If we would only believe God&#8217;s words more than we believe the words of the enemy our lives would be so different!</em></p></blockquote>



<h3 id="viewer-8255f"></h3>



<p id="viewer-5is2b">A few promise verses to get you started:</p>



<p id="viewer-9mko7"><strong>Nahum 1:7</strong> The Lord is good, a refuge in times of trouble. He cares for those who trust in Him.</p>



<p id="viewer-5vko0"><strong>Psalm 84:11</strong> For the Lord God is a sun and shield; the Lord bestows favour and honour; no good thing does He withhold from those whose walk is blameless.</p>



<p id="viewer-11r5c"><strong>Isaiah 40:29</strong> He gives strength to the weary and increases the power of the weak.</p>



<p id="viewer-1m6sg"><strong>Isaiah 40:31</strong> But those who hope in the LORD will renew their strength. They will soar on wings like eagles; they will run and not grow weary, they will walk and not be faint.</p>



<p id="viewer-6cb7i"><strong>Isaiah 43:2</strong> When you pass through the waters, I will be with you; and when you pass through the rivers, they will not sweep over you. When you walk through the fire, you will not be burned; the flames will not set you ablaze.</p>



<p id="viewer-1egg9"><strong>Deuteronomy 31:8</strong> The LORD Himself goes before you and will be with you; He will never leave you nor forsake you. Do not be afraid; do not be discouraged.</p>



<p id="viewer-9hna6"><strong>Joshua 1:9</strong> Have I not commanded you? Be strong and courageous. Do not be afraid; do not be discouraged, for the Lord your God will be with you wherever you go.</p>



<p id="viewer-e324"><strong>Philippians 4:6-7</strong> Do not be anxious about anything, but in every situation, by prayer and petition, with thanksgiving, present your requests to God. And the peace of God, which transcends all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.</p>



<p id="viewer-6sc2j"><strong>Proverbs 3:5-6</strong> &#8220;Trust in the Lord with all your heart and lean not on your own understanding; in all your ways submit to Him, and He will make your paths straight.&#8221;</p>



<p id="viewer-f27rn"><strong>John 8:12</strong> I am the light of the world. Whoever follows Me will never walk in darkness, but will have the light of life.</p>



<p id="viewer-9tbbh">These verses are just a small taste of the promises He has given us in His word. Find the verse that best suits your situation or circumstance and pray it over yourself regularly, out loud for all to hear. Make it your own and believe what is says. Take it to heart and watch as those giants fall.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/07/21/defeating-giants/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Knowing the father</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/07/21/knowing-the-father/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/07/21/knowing-the-father/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=373</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do you ever take time to just sit and think about God? Do you ever sit and think about what He has done for you? Do you ever really think...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_3ce2733ddb414b99b303956e7ac61ac1~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_614,h_408,al_c,lg_1,q_90/1bad17_3ce2733ddb414b99b303956e7ac61ac1~mv2.webp" alt="" width="848" height="563"/></figure>



<h3 id="viewer-1se1h"></h3>



<h3 id="viewer-4d397"><em>Do you ever take time to just sit and think about God?</em></h3>



<h3 id="viewer-bq1n5"></h3>



<h3 id="viewer-ag4pm"><em>Do you ever sit and think about what He has done for you?</em></h3>



<h3 id="viewer-511s8"></h3>



<h3 id="viewer-b2ft6"><em>Do you ever really think about what kind of person He is?</em></h3>



<p id="viewer-58o7h">This week I&#8217;ve been on a journey of rediscovery; reminiscing on what God has actually done for all humanity. I am absolutely blown away at the extravagance of my Lord. The lavishness of His mercy and love toward all humanity is outrageous. From the very beginning of time we see He is a Father who extends His hand to His creation in fellowship and seeks to form a relationship with us.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-8fivq">Genesis 3:8</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-625on"><em>And they heard the sound of the Lord God walking in the garden in the cool of the day&#8230;</em></h3>



<h3 id="viewer-a2k5k"></h3>



<h3 id="viewer-8mvqc">Genesis 3:9</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-59ujk"><em>Then the Lord God called to Adam and said to him, &#8220;Where are you?&#8221;</em></h3>



<p id="viewer-fmqmc">The Lord came to the garden. Adam and Eve did not come to Him. He came to them. He then called out to them to find out where they were. I don&#8217;t believe this was the first time He walked in the garden with them. I think He had done this before. He was expecting to see them. That is why He calls out to them.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-6m6hb"><p><em>How awesome that our God; our great King; would step down from His heavenly throne to walk with us and talk with us, to seek us out and call out our name.</em></p></blockquote>



<p id="viewer-6f35r">You know our God is so awesome that even after Adam and Eve sinned He put His divine plan into action to purchase us back from the hands of the enemy. He didn&#8217;t put a 12 step plan into place by which we could save ourselves and find a way to enlightenment or a higher spiritual plane. No! Our marvelous Father did it all. He made a way where there was no way, He straightened the crooked paths and set a rescue plan in place that would redeem the world back to Himself.</p>



<p id="viewer-k613">In the very beginning we catch a glimpse of the plan to come:</p>



<h3 id="viewer-eu1ms">Genesis 3:15</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-83bp3"><em>And I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your seed and her Seed; He shall bruise your head, and you shall bruise His heel.</em></h3>



<p id="viewer-9fb8e">God&#8217;s plan of redemption is perfect. Perfect in its execution, perfect in its design. The perfect King of Glory would do it all, for all who would believe.</p>



<p id="viewer-fo75v">Throughout the old testament we are shown the penalty of our sinful nature. The cost of sin upon our world. Countless animals were sacrificed to pay atonement for the sins of the people. The blood of the animals could not take away the sins of the people though, they only covered the sins for one year. This too was a foreshadow of what was to come. A picture of the sacrificial Lamb; the Lord Jesus who would come to earth as a perfect human, fully man. His perfection became the key to our salvation. He would walk in human flesh to be the one and only sacrifice for the entire world.</p>



<p id="viewer-9kk3n">Isaiah 53 foretells the coming Messiah &#8211;</p>



<h3 id="viewer-75mb5">Isaiah 53:4-6</h3>



<h3 id="viewer-egetf"><em>Surely He has borne our griefs and carried our sorrows; yet we esteemed Him stricken, smitten by God, and afflicted. But He was wounded for our transgressions, He was bruised for our iniquities. The chastisement for our peace was upon Him, and by His stripes we are healed. All we like sheep have gone astray, we have turned, every one, to his own way, and the Lord has laid on Him the iniquity of us all.</em></h3>



<p id="viewer-8d4n4">The Bible says He came to His own, but His own did not receive Him &#8211; John 1:11. He came knowing He would be rejected; knowing many of His beloved children would turn their backs on Him. He chose to come. He chose to see the redemption plan through to completion. The love He had for His children drove Him to the cross; drove Him to lay down His life that we might live.</p>



<h3 id="viewer-aa9ee"><em>John 1:11</em></h3>



<h3 id="viewer-5g9qv"><em>He came to His own, and His own did not receive Him. But as many as received Him, to them He gave the right to become children of God, to those who believe in His name; who were born, not of blood, nor of the will of the flesh, nor of the will of man, but of God.</em></h3>



<p id="viewer-df7h8">The cross of Calvary is where our rescue plan came to completion. That cruel cruel cross, where our Saviour was stretched out as a curse for us, that our curse would be lifted. He was covered in blood and tears; his heart aching from separation from His Father. His body racked with excruciating pain. All for us. All part of His perfect plan. He took upon Himself the sins of all the world. All the evil that was due us and all the punishment that was due us was placed upon His shoulders and laid upon His body. He paid the price for my sin and your sin.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-do928">What a Saviour!</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-728eg"></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-98nv6"><em>Beautiful Jesus!</em></h2>



<p id="viewer-bricf">What a beautiful Saviour He is. He not only came up with the rescue plan, but He followed through with the rescue plan to bring us back in to a right relationship with our Father in heaven. He has given us everything pertaining to life and godliness (2 Peter 1:3) and blessed us with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places in Christ (Ephesians 1:3). All this He has done for us, that we might live the life He died for us to have. All this He did for us that we would love Him and adore Him.</p>



<p id="viewer-455pr">All He asks is that we believe. Believe in Him; believe in what He has done for us; believe that His word speaks truth and life.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-7i2re">Do you know my Saviour? The One who laid everything down for you.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-fmuc1"></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-cg8c5">Do you hear Him calling your name?</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-4uc9g">Will you bend your knees and thank Him for all He has done and invite Him into your life?</h2>



<h3 id="viewer-4l535"></h3>



<h2 id="viewer-br7ds">Will you start your life anew, full of life and love; forgiven and redeemed?</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-dql0q"><em>Will you choose this day to believe He is who He says He is?</em></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-61a01">Will you believe He did it all for you?</h2>



<p id="viewer-ac8qo">He is never far from you and His heart&#8217;s desire is that you find Him.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-emd2i"><em>Acts 17:26-27</em></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-5ajfp"><em>And He has made from one blood every nation of men to dwell on all the face of the earth, and has determined their pre-appointed times and the boundaries of their dwellings, so that they should seek the Lord, in the hope that they might grope for Him and find Him, though He is not far from each of of us;&#8221;</em></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-ck49t">May you experience the extravagant love of God in a new way today. May you see Him with new eyes.</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-201sg"></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://www.fathersloveletter.com/
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/07/21/knowing-the-father/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Words, words, words&#8230;</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/07/21/words-words-words/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/07/21/words-words-words/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, this week has been a battle. A battle of the mind to actually write something on this blog. My mind has been full of words. Words that made sense...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-foo">Well, this week has been a battle. A battle of the mind to actually write something on this blog. My mind has been full of words. Words that made sense in my mind but once I typed them on the page they made no sense at all. Each time I would sit to type I would hear words like &#8211;</p>



<p id="viewer-7pu8l">&#8220;Who do you think you are?&#8221;</p>



<p id="viewer-bvc40">and</p>



<p id="viewer-7vd6g">&#8220;You can&#8217;t do this, you don&#8217;t have the wisdom for something like this.&#8221;</p>



<p id="viewer-c17rk">Words, words, words. Words that can destroy your confidence and steal your calling; rob your peace and kill your destiny.</p>



<p id="viewer-72n17">Jesus tells us in John 10:10</p>



<h2 id="viewer-3v16s"><em>&#8220;The thief does not come except to steal, and to kill, and to destroy. I have come that they may have life, and that they may have it more abundantly.&#8221;</em></h2>



<p id="viewer-65ibf">The thief only comes to steal what God has placed within us which is the hope of glory; to kill our faith in a loving Father; and to destroy our belief in God&#8217;s ability to transform us into the likeness of Jesus. If we listen to these words and allow them to settle in our hearts and minds then the thief has won. He gets the victory and we fall in defeat to fear, guilt, shame and regret.</p>



<p id="viewer-17gde">However, the second part of John 10:10 says</p>



<h2 id="viewer-6u15t"><em>&#8220;Jesus came that we may have life, and that we may have it more abundantly.&#8221;</em></h2>



<p id="viewer-c59c1">Hallelujah that our Lord Jesus came and died that we might live. He took all our shame, guilt, fear, and regret. He suffered a cruel death to pay for our sins. By His death we have life. We can live an abundant life because of what He did for us. His words for us are full of life and truth. Words of love and sacrifice. Words of power and authority. They are not empty words and empty promises.</p>



<p id="viewer-4l27u">Simon Peter said to Jesus in John 6:68 &#8211;</p>



<h2 id="viewer-5ce7s"><em>&#8220;Lord, to whom shall we go? You have the words of eternal life.&#8221;</em></h2>



<p id="viewer-crub6">We have a Saviour who knows everything that we go through, every giant that we face. He knows the struggles and battles we have endured and are still enduring. He doesn&#8217;t want us to fail; to fall to the enemy. He wants to equip us and arm us with words of power; words of life; words of transformation; words of hope. To equip us He gave us a manual for life; the word of God.</p>



<p id="viewer-20me9">Some time back I wrote in my Bible these words:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_b9d8a4b58d72427cb884ef74411daafc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_750,h_1000,al_c,q_20/file.jpg" alt=""/></figure>



<p id="viewer-50kkq">THIS IS MY MANUAL FOR LIFE! DO NOT FORGET TO READ IT AND FOLLOW IT&#8217;S INSTRUCTIONS! YOUR LIFE DEPENDS ON IT!</p>



<p id="viewer-9ohad">2 Timothy 3:16-17 also tells us &#8211;</p>



<h2 id="viewer-4kji"><em>&#8220;All scripture is given by inspiration of God, and is profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for correction, for instruction in righteousness, that the man of God may be complete, thoroughly equipped for every good work.&#8221;</em></h2>



<p id="viewer-a96fs">Our amazing Father, Saviour, and best friend has done everything possible for us to draw near to Him and experience His love and care for us. The Bible has an answer for all your questions and all your problems. For the Bible is the living word of God, inspired by God Himself. Try reading it for yourself today.</p>



<p id="viewer-2fsu6">Here is a couple of scriptures to help you get started with claiming back your stolen hope; for resurrecting your faith and rebuilding your relationship of trust with the Father to see transformation in your life; and to see you grow and mature in Him and all that He has called you to be.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-a2s7j">James 4:7</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-anl3a"><em>&#8220;Therefore, submit to God. Resist the devil and he will flee from you.&#8221;</em></h2>



<h2 id="viewer-dta6e">Revelation 12:11</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-6rd25"><em>&#8220;Overcome him [the enemy] by the blood of the Lamb and by the word of your testimony and do not love your life to the death.&#8221;</em></h2>



<p id="viewer-9f3qe">The enemy&#8217;s greatest fear is that we would awaken to the truth of who we really are. For each one of us is on the planet right now for such a time as this. Each one of us has a divine purpose and plan for our lives. Each one of us is precious in God&#8217;s eyes. He calls us by name. Yes He knows your name.</p>



<h2 id="viewer-ad5b2">Isaiah 43:1</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-be4ed">&#8220;But now, thus says the Lord, who created you, O Jacob, and He who formed you, O Israel, &#8220;Fear not, for I have redeemed you, I have called you by your name;</h2>



<h2 id="viewer-ei2pr">You are Mine.&#8221;</h2>



<p id="viewer-cl0d9">He calls to you today to come to Him.</p>



<p id="viewer-bbdf7">Thank you for reading my first official blog post. Bless you.</p>



<p id="viewer-crmhm">Please follow the link below to listen to Worthy of it All by Onething, David Brymer.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Worthy of It All (Live) - David Brymer" width="1080" height="608" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fff1c-HZf50?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p id="viewer-o9dg">Our Jesus is worthy of it all, so worthy of it all.</p>



<p id="viewer-bpgqn">Praise You Jesus.</p>



<p id="viewer-a4nsl">All glory, honour and praise is Yours forever and ever.</p>



<p id="viewer-ek2et">Amen</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/07/21/words-words-words/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I AM…</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/07/21/i-am/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/07/21/i-am/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a study I found on my shelf from way back! As I looked through it I was once again overwhelmed with the truth of these scriptures and wanted...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-foo"><strong>This is a study I found on my shelf from way back!</strong> <strong>As I looked through it I was once again overwhelmed with the truth of these scriptures and wanted to share them with you.</strong> <strong>This is not my own written study, so please forgive me for not crediting the original author but I don’t know who it was.</strong> <strong>If any of you know who the author is let me know.</strong> <strong>I hope you get as much from this study as I have.</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-fs54o"><strong>I AM SOMEBODY – I am a saint by God’s grace in Christ.</strong> Psalm 139:13-18 You made all the delicate, inner parts of my body and knit me together in my mother’s womb. Thank you for making me so wonderfully complex! Your workmanship is marvellous – how well I know it. You watched me as I was being formed in utter seclusion, as I was woven together in the dark of the womb. You saw me before I was born. Every day of my life was recorded in Your book. Every moment was laid out before a single day had passed. How precious are Your thoughts about me, O God. They cannot be numbered! I can’t even count them. They outnumber the grains of sand. And when I wake up You are still with me! Ephesians 2:8-10 God saved you by His grace when you believed. And you can’t take credit for this; it is a figt from God. Salvation is not a reward for the good things we have done, so none of us can boast about it. For we are God’s masterpiece. He has created us anew in Christ Jesus, so we can do the good things He planned for us long ago.</p>



<p id="viewer-7ak5b"><strong>I AM BLESSED AND HAVE ALL I NEED IN CHRIST.</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-csp5r">Colossians 2:9 For in Christ lives all the fullness of God in human body. <strong>I AM CHOSEN BY GOD</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-5t0cu">1 Peter 2:9 But you are not like that, for you are a chosen people. You are royal priests, a holy nation, God’s very own possession. As a result you can show others the goodness of God, for He called you out of the darkness into His wonderful light. Colossians 3:12 Since God chose you to be the holy people He loves, you must clothe yourselves with tender hearted mercy, kindness, humility, gentleness, and patience. John 15:15</p>



<p id="viewer-8bmac">I no longer call you slaves, because a master doesn’t confide in His slaves. Now you are my friends, since I have told you everything the Father told me. You didn’t chose me, I chose you. I appointed you to go and produce lasting fruit, so that the Father will give you whatever you ask for using My name. 1 Thessalonians 1:4 We know, dear brothers and sisters, that God loves you and has chosen you to be His own people.</p>



<p id="viewer-du532"><strong>I AM HOLY AND BLAMELESS IN HIS SIGHT</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-7kc4t">Romans 3:21-23 We are made right with God by placing our faith in Jesus Christ. And this is true for everyone who believes, no matter who we are, for everyone has sinned, we all fall short of God’s glorious standard. 1 Corinthians 1:30 God has united you with Christ Jesus. For our benefit God made Him to be wisdom itself. Christ made us right with God, He made us pure and holy and He freed us from sin. Ephesians 4:22-24 Throw off your old sinful nature and your former way of life, which is corrupted by lust and deception instead, let the Spirit renew your thoughts and attitudes. Put on your new nature, created to be like God, truly righteous and holy.</p>



<p id="viewer-c1buv"><strong>I AM A LOVED DAUGHTER/SON OF GOD</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-v3ei">Romans 8:15-17 So you have not received a spirit that makes you fearful slaves. Instead, you received God’s spirit when He adopted you as His own children. Now we call Him Abba Father, for His spirit joins with our spirit to affirm that we are God’s heirs. In fact together with Christ we are heirs of God’s glory. But if we are to share His glory, we must also share His suffering. 1 John 3:1 See how very much our Father loves us, for He calls us His children, and that is what we are! But the people who belong to this world don’t recognise that we are God’s children because they don’t know Him. 1 John 4:9-10 God showed how much He loved us by sending His one and only Son into the world so that we might have eternal life through Him. This is real love – not that we loved God, but that He loved us and sent His Son as a sacrifice to take away our sins. <strong>I AM A TROPHY OF THE GRACE OF GOD</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-8atnl">Ephesians 2:4 But God is so rich in mercy, and He loved us so much, that even though we were dead because of our Sins, He gave us life when He raised Christ from the dead. 1 Corinthians 15:1-11 By the grace of God, I am what I am. By His stripes I am healed. I may still have scars but the wound is healed. Why did Jesus choose to keep the scars? The scars were the story of the victory He had won.</p>



<p id="viewer-36tlk"><strong>I AM REDEEMED AND FORGIVEN</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-ac38m">Isaiah 53 Who has believed our message? To whom has the Lord revealed his powerful arm? My servant grew up in the Lord’s presence like a tender green shoot, like a root in dry ground. There was nothing beautiful or majestic about his appearance, nothing to attract us to him. He was despised and rejected—a man of sorrows, acquainted with deepest grief. We turned our backs on him and looked the other way. He was despised, and we did not care. Yet it was our weaknesses he carried; it was our sorrows that weighed him down. And we thought his troubles were a punishment from God, a punishment for his own sins! But he was pierced for our rebellion, crushed for our sins. He was beaten so we could be whole. He was whipped so we could be healed. All of us, like sheep, have strayed away. We have left God’s paths to follow our own. Yet the Lord laid on him the sins of us all. He was oppressed and treated harshly, yet he never said a word. He was led like a lamb to the slaughter. And as a sheep is silent before the shearers, he did not open his mouth. Unjustly condemned, he was led away. No one cared that he died without descendants, that his life was cut short in midstream. But he was struck down for the rebellion of my people. He had done no wrong and had never deceived anyone. But he was buried like a criminal; he was put in a rich man’s grave. But it was the Lord’s good plan to crush him and cause him grief. Yet when his life is made an offering for sin, he will have many descendants. He will enjoy a long life, and the Lord’s good plan will prosper in his hands. When he sees all that is accomplished by his anguish, he will be satisfied. And because of his experience, my righteous servant will make it possible for many to be counted righteous, for he will bear all their sins. I will give him the honours of a victorious soldier, because he exposed himself to death. He was counted among the rebels. He bore the sins of many and interceded for rebels.</p>



<p id="viewer-coee5">Colossians 1:10-14</p>



<p id="viewer-cqmbr">Then the way you live will always honour and please the Lord, and your lives will produce every kind of good fruit. All the while you will grow as you learn to know God better and better. We also pray that you will be strengthened with all His glorious power so you will have all the endurance and patience you need. May you be filled with joy, always thanking the Father. He has enabled you to share in the inheritance that belongs to His people, who live in the light. For He has rescued us from the kingdom of darkness and transferred us into the kingdom of His dear Son, who purchased our freedom and forgave our sins. <strong>I AM DEFENDED</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-c5u4d">Exodus 14:14</p>



<p id="viewer-b8s2c">The Lord will fight for you; and you shall hold your peace.</p>



<p id="viewer-1sk3u">Nehemiah 4:20</p>



<p id="viewer-dsi5o">Wherever you hear the sound of the trumpet, rally to us there.Our God will fight for us.</p>



<p id="viewer-cjrtd">Joshua 23:10</p>



<p id="viewer-frv23">One man of you shall chase a thousand, for the Lord your God is He who fights for you, as He promised you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/07/21/i-am/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introduction&#8230;</title>
		<link>./../../../2021/07/21/introduction/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2021/07/21/introduction/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=365</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I thought it appropriate to give a brief introduction as to who I am and what this blog is all about. I am a mother of 3 beautiful kids, living...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-foo">I thought it appropriate to give a brief introduction as to who I am and what this blog is all about.</p>



<p id="viewer-7foa9">I am a mother of 3 beautiful kids, living in the North East Coast of Scotland. I currently work for the NHS in a Covid Hub in Grampian. I started there in April 2020 at the beginning of our lockdown. Over the last 9 months we have experienced great highs and great lows. Unfortunately the fight is not over yet and tragically we are seeing tougher days now than ever before. I am blessed to have been a part of such a fantastic team at the Covid Hub and to witness the commitment and compassion of our fantastic NHS staff and the lengths they go to for patient care. I am super proud of you all and all you do.</p>



<p id="viewer-9aj12">I have felt the Lord nudge me for some time now to write a blog. I started a few times but never really had the words to say. In August 2020 I was blessed with a best friend; Arun Geet Mohan from india. We pray and study God&#8217;s word every day. He has inspired me, encouraged me, prayed for me and challenged me over the last four months. Growing with the Lord has given me the confidence to try this venture and hope that He steps in and fills the pages.</p>



<p id="viewer-ac0dt">So I am going to try and share my journey of faith with you. Share what I&#8217;m learning and hopefully help to encourage you and give you hope; leading to faith and belief. I believe that the greatest gift we can give to the Lord is faith and belief.</p>



<p id="viewer-8m8no">The Bible says in Hebrews 11:6</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1bad17_99f58104f7fc485a835fbffb305a5f9b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_750,h_1000,al_c,q_20/file.jpg" alt="" width="393" height="524"/></figure></div>



<p id="viewer-clghj">&#8220;And without faith it is impossible to please God. <em>Anyone who wants to come to Him must believe that God exists and that he rewards those who sincerely seek Him.</em>&#8220;</p>



<p id="viewer-64mem">The Lord wants to be found. He doesn&#8217;t want to be hidden from you. He wants you to search Him out.</p>



<p id="viewer-9g8ee">Jeremiah the old testament prophet said in chapter 29:13</p>



<p id="viewer-6s4l8">&#8220;<em>You will seek Me and find Me, when you search for Me with all your heart.</em>&#8220;</p>



<p id="viewer-d01el">I will not have all the answers, but my hope for this blog is to ignite faith, belief, passion and desire within you, that you would start to seek Him with all your heart and find your treasure.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2021/07/21/introduction/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
